[ phone ringing ]
[ ringing continues ]
[ " True Love " playing on speakers ]
[ ringing stops ]
- [ air hisses ] - [ phone ringing ]
[ ringing continues ]
- Hello ? - [ caller ] Hello .
Is Cristina there ?
No , she 's not available . May I take a message ?
[ caller ] Uh , yeah , well , um ...
Yeah , sorry . I 'm a friend from her group ...
Oh , shit .
From her shit ?
[ caller ] Um ... Look , just tell her I 'm from group .
I 'm Charlie . She 's got my number .
[ Tara ] Oh , she goes to your group ?
[ Charlie ] I shouldn 't have , um ...
Look , just tell her Charlie called .
And I will do exactly that , Charlie ,
once you tell me what kind of group we 're talking about .
- Is it AA ? NA ? - [ Charlie ] Look ...
You sound exactly like she describes you .
[ Tara ] Uh , does she talk about me in group ?
[ Charlie ] I don 't think I can really talk about that .
What does she say about me ?
Well , she loves you very much .
[ Tara ] What does she love about me ?
[ Charlie ] Oh , okay . Well ...
She loves that you 're creative .
You love art and TV and movies .
Okay , well , lots of people love movies .
[ Charlie ] Yeah , but she says you love scary movies
and that you guys have that in common .
She 's proud of making a fan out of you .
- She is ? - [ Charlie ] Yeah .
Well , she told me the other day , she wonders ...
what 's your favorite scary movie ?
Uh ... The Babadook .
It 's an amazing meditation on motherhood and grief .
[ Charlie laughs ]
Isn 't that a little fancy pants ?
Well , it 's elevated horror .
[ Charlie ] Uh-huh . What does that mean , " Elevated horror " ?
You know , it 's scary but with complex emotional and thematic underpinnings .
It 's not just some schlocky , cheeseball nonsense with wall-to-wall jump scares .
[ Charlie ] Hmm . Sounds kind of boring to me .
Have you ever seen Stab ?
Once , I think .
At a sleepover when I was , like , 12 .
[ Charlie ] You live in Woodsboro and you don 't know Stab ?
Your mother loves that movie .
She talks about it all the time in group .
How well do you remember the original ?
I don 't know .
I mean , it was super ' 90s .
It was really over-lit and everyone had weird hair .
Uh-huh . Do you remember the beginning ?
Not really .
It started with a kill scene , right ?
They always started with a kill scene .
[ Charlie ] Yeah , that 's right . That 's right .
It 's a girl at home , alone .
She answers a wrong number and starts talking with the killer
who makes her play a game .
Would you like to play a game ...
Tara ?
[ breathes heavily ]
[ automated voice ] All systems armed .
[ crickets chirping ]
[ phone beeps ]
- [ phone ringing ] - [ gasps , breathes heavily ]
[ ringing continues ]
[ phone beeps ]
This isn 't fucking funny , Amber .
[ Charlie ] I told you , this isn 't Amber .
[ phone chimes ]
[ Charlie ] Amber 's looking particularly fetching tonight .
She really shouldn 't leave her phone lying around for anyone to clone .
What do you want ?
[ Charlie ] I told you , I want to play a game .
Stab movie trivia , three rounds .
You call the cops , she dies .
You get a question wrong , she dies .
Her parents aren 't home .
I can be in that room in 15 seconds .
- [ Tara whimpers ] - You want a warmup question ?
I told you I don 't know these movies !
Ask me about something I do know .
Ask me about It Follows . Ask me about Hereditary .
Ask me about The Witch .
[ Charlie ] In the first Stab movie ,
what Woodsboro native was introduced
as the franchise 's main character ?
It 's Sidney Prescott !
It 's Sidney Prescott and she lived on Elm .
[ Charlie ] Correct . You see , you 're gonna do great at this .
Okay , question one ...
No , I got that one right . It should count .
[ Charlie ] Anyone could have gotten that one right .
Sidney 's in every movie but the last one .
Question one :
Who wrote the original book
that the Stab movies are based on ?
Um ... Um ...
The ... The chick from TV !
[ Charlie ] " The chick from TV " is not gonna cut it , Tara .
Gale Weathers !
It is Gale Weathers , you motherfucker !
[ Charlie ] Correct .
Amber might live to see the sunrise .
Question two : Who played the dumb bitch in the beginning of Stab 1
who answers the phone and gets carved up by the killer ?
Fuck you .
[ Charlie ] Is that the answer you 're going with ?
[ sobs ]
[ Charlie ] A non-answer counts as a wrong answer , Tara .
Time 's running out .
[ Charlie ] Ticktock , ticktock , ticktock , ticktock ...
Heather Graham !
[ Charlie ] Correct ! You pulled that one out .
Now for the final question :
- Who was the killer in Stab 1 ? - [ sobbing ]
Oh , I know this one , you fuck .
It 's Billy Loomis !
It 's Billy Loomis , and he was Sidney 's boyfriend ,
he was played by Luke Wilson , and I got you , asshole !
[ laughs ] I got it ! I got it right !
[ Charlie ] Oh , I 'm sorry , Tara , but that 's just not correct .
What ?
No , no , it is . It is . That is right .
[ Charlie ] The correct answer is Billy Loomis and Stu Macher .
There are two killers in the original Stab .
I 'm afraid someone 's got to die now .
No , no , no . Amber , I 'm coming .
Fuck , fuck , fuck .
[ screams ]
[ grunts ]
[ grunting , panting ]
[ sobbing ]
[ automated voice ] All systems armed .
[ beeping ]
- [ banging on door ] - [ whimpers ]
The police are on their way , asshole !
[ banging continues ]
[ sobbing ]
[ automated voice ] All systems disarmed .
[ automated voice ] All systems armed .
- All systems disarmed . - Oh , my God . No .
All systems disarmed . All systems armed .
All systems disarmed .
[ sobbing ]
[ automated voice ] All systems armed .
- [ phone ringing ] - [ screams ]
[ sobbing ]
[ continues ringing ]
Hello ?
[ Ghostface ] Bonus question , Tara .
Please stop .
[ Ghostface ] Do you think I made it inside your house
before you could rearm ?
[ screaming ]
[ Ghostface grunts ]
[ bone cracks ]
[ screams ]
[ screaming ]
[ sobbing ]
Help !
[ siren wailing ]
[ screams ]
[ Tara ] No ! No , no , no !
[ " Just Us " playing ]
[ Richie ] Excuse me , miss ?
- What 'd you just take ? - Your boner pills .
Good luck getting it up now .
You , um ...
You are my boner pills .
[ laughs ]
No . No .
- You okay ? - [ phone buzzing ]
Yes .
You don 't have to check on me all the time . I 'm not breakable .
Yeah , this I know .
Shit .
[ line ringing ]
- [ Wes ] Sam ? - Hey . What 's going on ?
[ Wes ] Uh , Tara ... was attacked .
What ? Is she ...
[ Wes ] She 's alive , but in bad shape .
She was ...
stabbed .
- Stabbed ? What the fuck ? - She made it through surgery
and the doctor said it went well .
She 's resting now .
I know you guys aren 't on the best terms , but ...
I 'm on my way .
[ Wes ] She 's gonna be okay , Sam . We 'll see you soon .
- Hey , wait , Wes ! - [ Wes ] Yeah ?
Do they know who did this ?
[ Wes ] It 's probably better if you just come here .
Wes .
[ Wes ] She said it was someone
in a fucking Ghostface mask .
My sister was attacked .
I gotta go .
Wait , hey ! Hey , hey hey . I 'm ... I 'm going with you .
- No . No , Richie ... - No , Sam . I 'm coming with you .
- Okay . - Okay . Yeah .
[ announcer over PA ] Attention , Panthers .
A reminder that all classes and school activities
are canceled tomorrow due to public safety concerns .
[ Wes ] That was Sam .
- She 's coming ? - [ Wes ] Yeah .
Watch everything get worse .
[ Chad ] All I 'm saying is , with everything going on right now ,
I think it 's time we take our relationship to the next , most intimate level .
He wants me to accept his Find My Fam request .
It 's the smartest option with a would-be killer on the loose .
You know exactly where I am and I know exactly where you are .
Aw , you can stalk me like a jealous boyfriend .
And you can stalk me like a jealous boyfriend .
[ retches , laughs ]
Is this because you two aren 't having sex yet ?
You bring up a very good point .
Not that I want to sound like a stereotypical jock
- trying to get into his girl 's pants ... - Great !
Don 't do it , Liv . There 's a psycho out there .
You make yourself harder to find .
Delete social media , tape over your phone camera ,
disable GPS .
Yes , thank you very much , Edward Snowden .
Actually , your mother just interrogated me about Tara 's attempted murder ,
which was very fun .
I 'm sure she 's asking everybody . I mean , Ghostface is back .
The press still isn 't saying Ghostface .
My mom doesn 't want to cause a panic .
It 'll get out by the second or third killing .
Jesus , Mindy , there wasn 't a first killing . Tara 's alive .
- Mmm . I mean , she could still die . - What the fuck ?
Or the killer could come back for her .
Fuck ! Mindy , come on .
I 'm just telling you , arm up , okay ?
Pepper spray , check . Taser , check .
Girlfriend repellent , check .
[ all laugh ]
[ Wes ] Nice . Thank you .
Holy shit . Is that ... Vince ?
[ Chad ] Wait . The creep you hooked up with last summer ?
- Yeah . He worked with me and Tara . - He worked with Tara ?
He 's been stalking my Instagram the last couple weeks ,
- posting the creepiest shit . - [ shutter clicks ]
Probably time to introduce him to Hobbs and Shaw .
Maybe not the best idea to incite violence
right in front of the sheriff .
Looks like he 's leaving .
Thanks anyways , boys .
[ Chad ] Yeah . Mm-hmm .
Hmm . Tara says she fought back hard .
You 've got bruises .
It 's from football practice .
- Oh , sure . - Tara 's awake . She just texted .
I 'm going to the hospital . You guys coming ?
- Yeah . - Yeah .
Oh , uh ... I can 't ,
but I 'll meet you guys there .
[ Chad ] All right .
- [ Richie ] I 've actually never seen Stab . - You 've never seen Stab ?
- Mmm . - Not even the one that came out last year ?
I 've never seen Gone with the Wind either ,
but I don 't consider it , like , a huge hole in my cinematic education .
Most of the Stab movies are based on things that happened here .
Define " things . "
Things like ...
a guy named Billy Loomis and his friend
carved up a bunch of high-school kids
while wearing this Halloween ghost mask .
You mean like in Halloween ?
- No . Not like in Halloween . - Oh .
Sounds a lot like Halloween .
- All right , it 's a little like Halloween . - Okay .
And every decade or so , some idiot gets the bright idea
to put on the mask , kill his friends , and get famous too .
The last time it happened was in 2011 .
And we came here voluntarily ?
Well , I got to make sure Tara 's okay .
Right . Yes , of course .
And I got to make sure we don 't get sliced up by some lunatic
who saw Friday the 13th and thought , " You know what ?
That Jason guy , he 's got some pretty solid ideas . "
Can I ask you one question though ?
Yeah .
Do you have any idea why
someone wearing that mask would want to kill your sister ?
No .
How are you feeling ?
You came .
Of course I came .
This is my boyfriend , Richie .
It 's so nice to meet you . I 'm so sorry if I 'm intruding .
Nice to meet you too .
Hi .
- Thank you for calling . - Of course .
Look at your hair ! I like it .
These are Chad and Mindy , the twins . And Wes .
I used to babysit them all .
Which is always how I like to be introduced .
[ chuckles ]
And Amber . Hey .
Hi . Nice to see you .
Hi . I 'm Richie .
Hi .
Where 's Mom ?
[ Tara ] She 's stuck at a conference in London .
She called me earlier .
Yeah , for all of ten minutes .
Uh , look , guys , Tara 's really tired .
Maybe we should just give her some space .
Yeah .
- Yeah . - Yeah .
Not you , Sam .
I want you to stay .
Okay .
- But the rest . - Yeah .
If it 's okay with you , I could sleep here tonight .
I 'd really like that .
Okay .
- Do you have your extra inhaler ? - I 'll be fine .
Bye .
- Okay , I 'll be right outside . - Thank you .
[ Richie ] Bye .
[ door closes ]
Sam , I was so scared .
[ whispers ] I know . It 's okay .
[ sobbing ]
So what is she like , the sister ?
Sam ? Oh , Sam is so cool .
You only say that because she let you
wear Pokémon onesies to bed for a year .
- True . That 's a true statement . - [ all laugh ]
No , trust me . Sam is not cool . Her dad left her mom , right ?
Walks right out when Tara 's eight , Sam 's 13 .
Sam started acting out , getting in trouble with the cops .
And then , on Sam 's 18th birthday , she leaves .
Ghosts them all .
Maybe Sam 's changed .
I just don 't want to see Tara hurt again .
So what , you 're protecting Tara from her own sister now ?
Well , someone has to .
Okay , so no guys are good enough for her ,
and now her family 's off-limits too ?
[ Mindy ] Mmm , motive .
" If I can 't have her , no one can . "
What ?
We know you have a crush on Tara .
Okay . Come on , Mindy .
But we 're all suspects .
- Except maybe Liv . - Thank you .
You 're way too boring to be a psycho .
Yo , Liv . You want a real drink ?
Or are you happy sitting at this kids ' table ?
Listen up , uglier Michael Myers , it was a summer fling .
- It meant nothing . - Was I talking to you ?
I don 't care who you 're talking to .
- Liv , let 's go . - Don 't talk to her !
I don 't want to hear your voice .
- Shut the fuck up . - [ bartender ] Hey !
Get out of here or I 'm calling the cops .
Go !
- I 'll see you soon , sweetheart . - Hey , man , fuck you .
[ bartender ] You kids too ! Let 's go !
Do you see this shit ?
Fuck this bar , man .
Fuck you .
Fuck it !
[ car engine revving ]
What the fuck ?
[ " Red Right Hand " playing on stereo ]
[ revving continues ]
What the fuck ?
Is that you , pretty boy ? Huh ?
Get out of my fucking car !
- [ engine stops ] - [ music stops ]
[ sighs ]
[ music resumes ]
[ gurgles ]
[ gasps ]
Hey .
- You okay ? - Yeah .
Just a bad dream .
What are you watching ?
Oh , Stab is on Netflix .
What ? I want to be prepared .
I got to go find something to eat .
Yeah , okay .
How you doing , Sam ?
Mmm . Antipsychotics aren 't working as well as they used to , are they ?
Fuck you .
You can 't run from who you are , Sam .
I 'm just trying to help .
Hey , when are you gonna tell her why all this is happening ?
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ PA Announcement ] Blue team , ICU .
[ ringing continues ]
Hello .
[ Ghostface ] Hello , Samantha .
Who is this ?
[ Ghostface ] Someone who knows your little family secret .
You 're the fuck who hurt my sister ?
[ Ghostface ] Oh , she 's not the only one I 'm gonna hurt .
I had to get you to come back here somehow , didn 't I ?
You want to fuck with me , asshole ?
I 'm right here . Come and get me .
[ Ghostface ] With pleasure .
[ Sam screams ]
[ Sam grunts ]
Help !
Help ! Help !
Somebody help me ! He 's trying to kill me !
What 's going on ? You 're okay .
Somebody tried to kill me in the break room !
[ Sheriff ] I 've got a body outside a bar on Main ,
and now you get attacked here .
You said the call came from Amber 's number ?
So ? We know he cloned my phone before when he attacked Tara .
Or , and I 'm just spit-balling here ...
you 're the killer .
And where were you when all this happened ?
I was ... watching Netflix .
- Yeah . Super-solid alibi , bro . - So where were you ?
[ Sheriff ] I was questioning her at the sheriff 's station .
[ Amber ] Yeah , I came as soon as I heard .
But , you know , the Netflix alibi is good , too .
Both of you , stop it .
You 're gonna put more cops on her room , right ?
[ Sheriff ] Yes .
And I can move you to a private floor .
Deputy Vinson knows what he 's doing . You 'll be safe .
Like we 've been so far ?
Samantha , let 's step outside .
Nice to see you , Deputy Hicks .
- So many fun memories . - It 's " Sheriff " Hicks .
I remember you too ...
and all the trouble you used to cause your family .
Your presence here is not helping .
So maybe when the sun comes up ,
you and your boyfriend can hit the road
and leave it to people who actually care about this community .
[ scoffs ]
Well , she remains a delight .
Are you okay ?
Um , would you mind giving us a second ?
I need to talk to Tara .
Come on , Netflix . Let 's go .
[ scoffs ]
Do you remember when Dad left ?
Parts , sure .
I was eight . I don 't know what that has to do with anything .
It has to do with it .
Do you remember how ...
Mom used to keep those boxes up in the attic ?
Well , I was up there once ,
when I was 13 , looking for Christmas presents .
And I found these old diaries that she kept from high school .
- Sam , what is ... - Please .
I just ... I have to do this .
So I found these old diaries .
And I knew it was wrong , but I read some anyway
because Mom got pregnant with me in high school ,
and I thought it could be cool to find out how she and Dad got together .
How romantic it must have been .
So I read some .
Only it wasn 't romantic .
Mom was dating Dad , but ...
she was in love with this other guy ...
and he got her pregnant .
She told Dad it was his ,
and that 's why he proposed senior year .
Sam , what are you talking about ?
And I 'm sitting there , in this attic ,
and I 'm 13 ...
and I just found out my dad isn 't my dad .
So I go find Mom in her bedroom , and I 'm screaming at her
and shoving this diary in her face ,
and I didn 't even realize ...
that Dad was standing right behind me .
He didn 't know .
He found out right then from me .
He left that night .
I 'm the reason he left .
No .
- No , Sam ... - Mom never forgave me .
Then she made me promise never to tell you because you were so young .
And that 's why I changed
and I got distant and weird with you .
And I went out and I started doing
every drug that I could get my hands on
until I couldn 't take it anymore and I left town .
I just couldn 't be around you anymore , Tara .
Not only because I destroyed our family that night ,
but because ...
those diaries told me who my real father was .
It was Billy Loomis .
And somebody knows ,
and I think that 's why you got hurt .
And I 'm so fucking sorry that I never told you and that I ran away .
- I 'm so sorry . - Get out .
Tara .
You 're gone for five years ...
Five whole years .
And then I get stabbed and you want to come back
and drop all this shit on me ?
- I thought I was protecting you . - Protecting me from what ?
The truth ?
No .
- No , I ... Please , Tara . - Sam .
- I need you to get the fuck out . - I 'm so sorry .
- Sam . - Please .
Get the fuck out !
[ door opens , closes ]
[ cries ]
- [ gasps ] - Hey , hey . It 's okay , it 's me .
Were you listening at the door ?
No , no , of course not .
Okay , yeah , I was listening at the door .
It doesn 't freak you out ...
that my real father was a serial killer ?
I mean ...
yeah .
A great deal , yeah .
Okay , well , then go . I get it .
I just got to stay and figure it out .
I 'm not leaving you here , Sam .
You know that part in horror movies
where you want to yell at the characters to be smart
and get the fuck out ?
This is that part , Richie .
You should get the fuck out .
But I 'm staying .
I love you .
- You 're such a dumbass . - I 'm such a dumbass .
So ...
your sister won 't talk to you .
The police aren 't gonna help .
What 's our next move ?
We go talk to an expert .
[ birds chirping ]
[ weather reporter ] ... temperatures here Tuesday , Wednesday in the mid-50s ,
and then finally we 'll see those mid-60s returning next week .
[ news anchor ] Just one night after a local teen was attacked in her home
by an assailant wearing a Ghostface costume ,
Sheriff Judy Hicks has now confirmed two more late-night attacks
that have left Woodsboro reeling .
The first victim , Vincent Schneider ,
was found dead behind the Corner Pocket Pool Hall .
A second victim , as yet unnamed ,
was attacked inside Woodsboro General Hospital , but escaped without injuries .
Needless to say , Woodsboro is on high alert today ...
[ TV announcer ] Live from Studio 1-A in Rockefeller Plaza ...
Good morning . I 'm Gale Weathers .
Before we dive in , I want to tell you a little story
that happened on the way into the studio this morning .
- I stopped to get a bacon ... - [ knocking on door ]
... at a bodega , already a quintessentially New York ...
Go away !
[ Sam ] Sorry to bother you , Mr. Riley !
We just want to ask you a few questions .
[ Dewey ] I don 't give interviews .
We 're not looking for an interview .
[ footsteps approaching ]
Give me one good reason why I should talk to you .
I 'm Billy Loomis 's daughter .
That 's a terrible reason for me to talk to you .
My name is Samantha Carpenter .
I was attacked last night at the hospital .
The night before that , my sister was stabbed seven times .
I know you know what that 's like .
[ sighs ]
I 'm just trying to protect my family .
Five minutes . That 's all I 'm asking .
I 'll give you two minutes .
I 'm missing a show I like .
... bangs again , stage an intervention .
[ Richie ] Gale Weathers .
- Weren 't you two , um ... - Yeah .
Who 's he ?
Oh , this is Richie , my boyfriend .
How long have you known him ?
Six months ?
Did he know who your dad was when you met ?
Express any interest in Woodsboro
or the Ghostface killings ?
What the hell are you talking about ?
Your killer 's obsessed with the Stab movies , right ?
Well , there are certain rules to surviving a Stab movie .
Believe me , I know .
Rule number one :
Never trust the love interest .
They seem sweet , caring , supportive . Then welcome to act 3 ,
where they 're trying to rip your head off .
I was with Sam in Modesto when Tara was attacked .
And let me guess , you were just in the other room ,
conveniently unaccounted for when she was attacked at the hospital .
Okay , do I have to take this from shitty Sam Elliott over here , or what ?
- Rule number two ... - [ scoffs ]
... the killer 's motive is always connected to something in the past .
- I 'm related to Billy . - Right ,
but then why kill that random Vince guy ?
That 's for you to figure out .
And rule number three , and this is the most important rule :
The first victim always has a friend group that the killer is a part of .
Does your sister have a close-knit group of friends ?
Yeah .
She does .
Then look for the killer there .
If you can find out why they 're doing this ,
you can figure out who 's next .
So help us .
Help us figure out who is behind this .
You kidding me ? I 've been stabbed nine times .
I 've got permanent nerve damage and a fun little limp .
You think I want to do that again ?
You just said it always goes back to the past , right ?
So if I 'm in danger ...
that means you 're in danger .
Come on .
Let 's do this together .
Your time 's up .
- [ door slams ] - Jesus !
[ sighs ]
Yeah , he 's way more fun in the movies .
Okay , uh , what 's next ?
The friends .
[ new anchor ] Thanks so much for that , Kevin .
Coming up after our local weather ,
the pros and cons of reuniting with old friends .
[ TV clicks off ]
[ sighs ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
Hello ?
[ Dewey ] Hey , Sid , it 's me .
Dewey ? [ chuckles ]
Oh , my God . How long has it been ?
I 'm just trying to get a run in before I take the girls to school .
How are you ?
I 'm good , really good .
How are you ? How 's Mark ?
I think I 'll keep him .
How are things in the sheriff 's business ?
Uh , they 're ...
- They 're fine . But , Sid ... - Have you talked to Gale lately ?
No . Not in a couple years .
I know things didn 't end well with you guys , but ...
Sid ...
it 's happening again .
What are you talking about ?
[ Dewey ] Some idiot in a Ghostface mask .
Three attacks so far . One dead .
Something about this one just feels different .
Are you okay ?
[ Dewey ] I 'm fine , you know me .
Yeah .
I do . That 's why I 'm asking .
I 'm fine .
I just ...
want you to be safe up there . Do you have a gun ?
I 'm Sidney fucking Prescott . Of course I have a gun .
[ chuckles ]
Good . That 's good .
[ sighs ] Does Gale know ?
No , she 's my next call .
But , Sid , promise me :
No matter what you hear or what you see on the news ,
don 't come here .
No offense , Dewey . I have no intention
of ever setting foot in that town again .
Good .
Dewey ...
whoever this killer 's after , I 'm glad they have you to protect them .
But ...
you be safe , okay ?
Will do .
[ Sidney ] It 's good to hear your voice .
You too , Sid .
Come on . Get it together , Dewey .
[ breathes deeply ]
[ grunts ]
[ groans ]
Probably shouldn 't have sent the smiley face .
[ sighs ]
[ car approaching ]
[ car stops ]
[ car door opens , slams ]
Holy shit . He came .
I 've decided to temporarily assist you in your investigation .
Thank you .
Look , just because that guy showered
doesn 't mean he should have a gun .
- [ Sam ] Yeah . - [ Richie ] Yeah .
[ chattering ]
[ Richie ] How do you know so much about the Stab movies ?
[ Dewey ] Runs in her family .
Randy was our uncle .
RIP . [ kisses ]
[ Mindy ] You said to bring everybody .
[ Sam ] Hey .
Ooh , suspects !
My brother would be so proud .
Hey , Martha .
Dewey ! Hi !
You look ...
Yeah .
How 's the wife ?
Mom , we 're good . Thank you .
All right , kids , have fun .
I asked Mindy to call everybody here , because ...
there 's something I have to tell you .
[ Chad ] Let me get this straight .
You 're saying that you 're the daughter of Billy Loomis ,
and , what , that one of us is the killer ?
The killer told me he knew my secret .
He attacked Tara to lure me back here .
[ Chad ] But then why immediately go and murder
some douche-nozzle that was stalking Liv ?
[ Wes ] And why does it have to be one of us ?
What about Deputy Dewey here ? Maybe he 's the killer .
No offense .
None taken , but what 's my motive ?
You got stabbed a billion times ,
got dumped by your famous wife and crawled into a bottle .
I think it 's safe to say you 're on the suspect list .
Well , maybe you 're the killer .
Because that cut deep .
[ Amber ] That douche-nozzle is connected .
I googled him . His mom is Leslie Macher .
- Stu Macher 's sister . - Who 's Stu Macher ?
He 's Billy Loomis 's accomplice .
A real loony tune .
Okay . Okay .
So the first three attacks are all on people related to the original killers .
Oh , my God . He 's making a requel !
A what ?
Or a legacyquel .
Fans are torn on the terminology .
Please speak English .
Remember the Stab movie
that came out last year ?
Oh , yeah !
The one the Knives Out guy directed ?
I actually really liked that one .
Of course you did . You have terrible taste .
I hate you .
The point is , the hard-core Stab fans hated it .
You go on 4chan and Dreadit ,
all they 're talking about is how Stab 8
pissed on their childhoods .
How they crammed in social commentary just to elevate it .
How the main character 's a Mary Sue .
- What 's a Mary Sue ? - You really don 't want to know .
What 's wrong with elevated horror ?
I mean , Jordan Peele fucking rules .
Uh , obviously , but that 's not Stab .
Real Stab movies are meta slasher whodunits , full stop .
- Come on . It 's just a movie . - No , it 's not .
To some people , the original is their favorite thing in the world .
The movie that made them love horror .
That Mom or Dad showed them when they were ten that bonded them together .
And God help anyone who slightly fucks with that special memory .
Who makes a movie they think disrespects it .
It sounds like our killer is writing his own version of Stab 8 ,
but doing it as a requel .
Which is ?
See , you can 't just reboot a franchise from scratch anymore .
The fans won 't stand for it .
Black Christmas , Child 's Play , Flatliners ...
That shit doesn 't work .
But you can 't just do a straight sequel , either .
You got to build something new .
But not too new , or the Internet goes bug-fucking nuts .
It got to be part of an ongoing story line ,
even if the story shouldn 't have been ongoing in the first place .
New main characters , yes ,
but supported by and related to legacy characters .
Not quite a reboot , not quite a sequel .
Like the new Halloween , Saw ,
Terminator , Jurassic Park , Ghostbusters ...
fuck , even Star Wars !
It always , always goes back to the original !
Are you telling me that I 'm caught in the middle of fan-fucking-fiction ?
Not just in the middle , Sam .
You 're the star .
So , not to put too fine a point on it ,
but , according to requel rules ...
[ sighs ] ... who 's next ?
Going by the pattern ,
whoever it is has to be connected to someone that came before .
I 'm starting to regret coming here .
Jesus , my mom was a character in one of them .
No one cares about the shitty inferior sequels , Wes .
You 're safe .
With Randy as our uncle , though ,
you and I are probably screwed .
- Wait . What ? - Or you 're the killer ,
and this whole elaborate monologue is just to cover your tracks .
[ scoffs ] I think it 's pretty clear who the killer is at this point .
Who ?
You .
What ...
It makes perfect requel sense .
- That actually does make sense . - Yeah .
[ scoffs ] Fuck this .
- Meet you back at the motel . - [ Richie ] Sam , wait .
Sam , wait .
The first fucking rule of these movies is don 't split up !
The nerve of that girl , right ?
[ sighs ] Really not in the mood right now .
[ Billy ] Sam , Sam , Sam .
There is a killer on the loose .
He 's threatening you . He 's threatening your sister .
Are you gonna run away from who you are like you always do ,
or are you gonna use it ?
I 'm not like you .
Really ?
Then how else are you gonna survive ?
I say accept who you are , let 's get out there , find out who 's doing this ,
and cut some fucking throats !
- No ! - [ honking ]
[ tires screech ]
[ panting ]
Mmm . And extra edamame . Please .
Thank you . I 'll be there in ten minutes .
Bye .
[ door opens ]
That you , tiger ?
[ door creaks ]
[ breathes heavily ]
[ lock clicks ]
- [ gasps ] - Jesus !
- [ clears throat ] - [ scoffs ]
Are you being safe out there , honey ?
[ scoffs ] To the point that all my friends mock me , yes .
Good boy .
What 's for dinner ?
Sushi . I was just leaving to pick it up .
Oh . Why don 't you just Postmates it ?
Oh , it gets all smooshy by the time it 's here .
- I know you hate that . - [ chuckles ]
- Go shower . I 'll be back soon . - Okay .
- Can you put this away for me ? - Yes .
- Okay . - [ Judy chuckles ]
- Love you . - Love you .
- Lock the door . - I will .
[ water running ]
[ police radio chatter ]
[ chattering ]
[ phone rings ]
Sheriff Hicks .
[ Ghostface ] Hello , Sheriff Judy .
- Who is this ? - I think you know .
I 'm a fan of scary movies . And knives .
What 's your favorite scary movie ?
I prefer animated films and musicals .
Why are you doing this ?
I 'll tell you all about it . I 'm calling to turn myself in .
I think that 's a great idea .
We 'll sit down at the station ,
and I 'll tell you about the two people I 've killed .
You 've only killed one person .
[ Ghostface laughs ] By the time I see you ,
I 'll have gutted your baby boy .
- No . - [ siren wailing ]
[ pedestrian ] Whoa .
Fuck you !
Pick up , Wes !
[ phone buzzing ]
[ Wes whistling ]
This is Sheriff Hicks .
I need units to converge on my house ASAP .
- [ officer ] Copy that . We 're on it . - [ phone rings ]
[ Ghostface ] Can 't get him on the phone , can you ?
He must be busy .
How do I know you 're anywhere near him ?
[ Ghostface ] Ever seen the movie Psycho ?
Please ...
don 't hurt my boy .
[ Ghostface ] Why not ?
- He 's a good kid . - Is he , now ?
He never hurt anyone .
[ Ghostface ] That 's not enough .
Please ! I 'll do anything !
You 're not gonna make it in time , Sheriff Judy .
[ engine roars ]
[ door creaks in distance ]
[ siren stops ]
Wes !
I 'm coming !
[ grunts , pants ]
Help !
[ grunts ]
[ choking ]
[ thuds ]
[ humming ]
Okay .
[ chuckles ]
[ door opens ]
Mom ?
[ Wes screams ]
[ grunts ]
Fuck ... you !
[ sirens wailing in distance ]
[ police radio chatter ]
Miss , you can 't be here . You can 't be here .
No , I 'm sorry . I know her son .
- Her son , Wes . Is he ... - I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry .
Excuse me .
Oh , my God .
You 're ...
Well , you 're you .
Last time I checked .
Are you okay ? You seem like you 're having a bit of a moment .
Did you know the sheriff ?
Sort of .
She didn 't like me very much .
She didn 't like me either .
Um ... I 'm Samantha . Sam . Carpenter .
My sister and I were attacked .
Oh . Sorry to hear that .
I 'm Gale ...
Riley .
Weathers . I 'm Gale Weathers . Excuse me .
Gale ?
- A text ? - Ow .
You tell me the killer is back in a text ?
- Ow , that hurts . - Good !
- You were on the air . - How do you know ?
A hunch . [ chuckles ]
You look good . Are you still writing ?
No time .
You were always happiest when you were writing .
[ man ] Well , sir , it 's okay . We 're here with Gale .
[ woman ] I 'd give you a hand , but I can 't release anybody right now .
Couldn 't resist a good story , could you ?
Don 't be an idiot , Dewey .
I 'm here because I was worried about you .
- [ scoffs ] - Okay , yes .
My producers wanted me to cover this , for obvious reasons ,
but 90 % is because of you .
Well , I feel 90 % better .
Don 't be so sensitive .
Since when did you care about my feelings ?
Especially not in the last couple years .
All right , listen . Let 's not pretend I 'm the one who ended things .
No one 's pretending , Gale . I remember what happened .
[ stammers ] Why aren 't you in uniform ?
I retired .
Since when ?
Since they asked me to .
Oh , Dewey .
I don 't need your pity , Gale .
I made my choices . So did you .
It was my turn . It was a great opportunity .
- You said you 'd try . - And I did .
For two whole months !
Listen , if you want to make me feel worse
than I already do , good luck .
The mornings aren 't so bad , ' cause I get to see you .
Pretend I 'm still back there in New York .
But then I remember ...
that I couldn 't hack it .
I left in the middle of the night ...
like a coward .
Why wouldn 't you tell me that then ?
It would have mattered .
You are a lot of things , Dewey ...
but you are not a coward .
You just ...
You just were meant to be in Woodsboro .
And you weren 't ?
Promise me you 'll leave as soon as you can .
You know I can 't promise that .
I 'm sorry about Judy .
Yeah , me too .
But she 'll make a great chapter in your next book .
[ screaming ]
[ fan 1 ] And don 't even get me started
on Ghostface 's signature new weapon .
[ Ghostface actor ] That shit is lit .
And can we talk about the title ? Stab ?
What , just like the original ?
Just call it Stab 8 . It 's fucking Stab 8 .
- [ ring tone plays ] - You 're not fooling anyone .
[ fan 1 ] It 's such bullsh ...
[ Richie ] Where have you been ? You okay ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
That Mindy girl wasn 't kidding .
Stab 8 is not like the others .
I mean , no connection to the other movies .
- No legacy characters at all . - [ Sam ] Richie .
If you ask me , this franchise goes off the rails with number five .
Richie , listen to me . He killed two more people .
Wes and his mother .
[ Richie ] He killed the sheriff ? You can do that ?
I mean , are you okay ? Where are you ?
- I 'll call you right back . - [ Richie ] No , Sam ...
Who 's at the hospital ?
Who 's watching my sister ?
I just heard about the sheriff .
[ scoffs ]
They needed me here !
- Where are you going ? - My sister 's in trouble !
[ Gale ] ... where Judy Hicks has just been brutally murdered .
What are you waiting for ? Drive !
Come on . Let 's go !
- Are the doors locked ? - Yeah , we should check .
Joey and Pacey , check the front door . Jen and Cliff , get flashlights ...
[ grunt , thud in distance ]
- [ Ursula on TV ] Where you going ? - Hello ?
[ Dawson on TV ] You stay there .
[ Ursula on TV ] No , I 'm coming with you .
[ Dawson ] Okay .
[ Pacey on TV ] He 's got you .
Hello ?
[ Joey on TV ] No , I 'm not .
[ Pacey on TV ] Please . Quit tripping out .
This is just Dawson up to his old tired tricks .
There 's no psychopath in this house .
[ Joey on TV ] Yes , there is . And you brought her .
Fuck this .
[ monitor beeping ]
[ beeping stops ]
[ conversation continues on TV ]
[ groans , grunts ]
Fuck !
[ gasps ] Oh !
[ groaning ]
[ yelps ]
[ sobbing ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ ringing continues ]
Goddamn it !
Should you really be making a phone call right now ?
- [ line ringing ] - Please , please .
[ car horn blares ]
[ Tara groans ]
[ sobs ]
- [ gasps ] - [ gurgling ]
- [ car horn blares ] - [ tires screech ]
Stop ! You know we have to live through this to help her , right ?
Just hold on .
[ sobs ]
- [ door opens in distance ] - [ gasps ]
[ crying ]
- [ squelches ] - [ crying ]
[ phone beeping ]
- [ door opens , closes ] - [ whispers ] Holy shit .
[ whimpers ]
[ door opens ]
[ door closes ]
[ footsteps approach ]
Ow ! Ow .
- Goddamn it ! [ sighs ] - Richie ?
What are you doing here ?
Sam called . She said that ...
you were in trouble .
- Did you hit me with the phone ? - Look out !
[ Richie screams ]
[ Tara screams ]
[ sobbing ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ crying ]
[ device powers up ]
Richie !
- Are you at the hospital ? - [ Ghostface ] Hello , Samantha .
[ Ghostface ] Richie can 't come to the phone right now .
He 's finding out what happens to people
who stick their noses in business that doesn 't concern them .
- [ Sam ] Please don 't hurt him . - Tell you what . You can choose .
I 'll only kill one .
[ Sam ] What ? What ? Tera !
[ Ghostface ] Who do you want to hear die ?
[ Sam ] No . Please ! I 'm begging you . Please don 't hurt them .
[ Ghostface ] Really ? You can 't save your own sister ?
All you have to do is say , " Kill Richie . "
- [ Sam ] No ! - [ Tara screams ]
[ Sam ] Tara ! Don 't touch her !
Please , please , please . I 'm begging you .
[ Ghostface ] Or say , " Kill Tara , "
and I 'll make sure to hit all the organs I missed last time .
- [ Sam ] No ! - Fuck you !
[ Sam ] I 'm begging you . Please don 't hurt her .
[ Ghostface ] Last chance to save one . Choose !
[ Sam ] Why are you doing this ?
You want to know why , Sam ?
Maybe it 's because you 're a selfish bitch
who can 't even make a decision to save the life of someone you love .
Maybe you 're too weak for this franchise .
[ Sam ] Maybe you 're right .
Or maybe I 'm just stalling for time , fuckhead .
[ elevator dings ]
[ bullet ricochets ]
I 'll get Richie .
[ Sam ] Tara !
Oh , my God !
[ sobs ]
- Come on . - [ groans ]
It 's okay . I got you .
It 's gonna be all right .
- Get the elevator ! - [ shouting ]
[ Dewey strains ]
[ Dewey grunts ]
Not today .
Richie .
[ Tara sobbing ]
- Come on , hurry up . - [ Tara ] Oh !
- The head . - What ?
You have to shoot ' em in the head , or they always come back .
Dewey ! Who gives a fuck ?
- I do . - [ Sam ] No ! Dewey !
[ cell phone rings ]
[ grunts ]
[ groans ]
Yes , today .
[ cell phone rings ]
[ Ghostface ] It 's an honor .
[ sirens wailing ]
No !
No ! No !
[ Sam ] I 'm sorry .
I didn 't know him well , but ...
he helped me .
That 's what he did . [ sniffles ]
He helped people .
I should 've stopped him .
If you had , my sister would be dead .
[ nurse ] Samantha , your sister 's awake .
[ Sidney ] Gale .
Sidney .
I came as soon as I heard .
I 'm so sorry .
You shouldn 't be here .
You shouldn 't be here either .
- Mark and the kids are okay ? - Yeah , they 're safe for now .
I 'm here to make sure of that .
Come here .
[ sighs ]
[ police radio chatter ]
How you feeling ?
Every time I get attacked ,
they give me better painkillers .
So there 's that .
I 'm sorry .
For what ? You saved my life .
For not telling you sooner .
For being the reason Dad left .
You 're not the reason Dad left .
You didn 't choose where you came from . Or who you came from .
I don 't blame you for that .
I blame you for leaving me too .
That 's never gonna happen again .
I know .
But why didn 't you come to me back then ?
I could 've helped .
Because ...
I was scared .
Of what ?
I was scared that I would turn out just like him .
So I ran .
To protect you .
From me .
Sam ...
you could never be like him .
- You 're so high right now . - I 'm so high right now .
- [ chuckles ] - I 'm not even gonna lie .
I love you .
I love you too .
So what do we do now ?
What nobody ever does in these situations .
We 're gonna get the fuck out of Woodsboro .
- That 's her ? - Yeah .
Samantha ?
It 's Sam .
- I 'm ... - I know who you are .
I hope you 're okay .
- Listen , I 'm sorry ... - You 're Billy 's daughter .
We 'll bring the car around .
Yeah . I 'm his daughter .
I 'm sorry if that 's weird for you .
No , no , it 's ...
I 've been through this . A lot .
You want to talk ?
I appreciate it .
And I 'm ...
I 'm really sorry about Dewey .
But I 'm taking my sister away from all this .
I tried running too .
It doesn 't work , it always follows .
All due respect , that 's your life , not mine .
- I 'm not so sure about that . - What do you want from me , lady ?
Hey ! Watch your tone , new girl .
You know how they always say it goes back to the original ?
Here 's the original .
I want your help .
Because you 're wrong , this is your life now .
Which means whoever this is will keep coming for you .
- So ? - So I want you to help us kill him .
You want me to help you and the host of a morning show commit murder ?
- Correct . - Yeah .
And I 'm what in this scenario ?
The bait ? The helpless victim ?
- If the shoe fits ... - You 're not helpless , Sam .
He killed your friend , he killed ours .
And I have kids , which means I won 't sleep until he 's in the ground .
Look , I 'm sorry about what this has done to your lives .
But no matter what you or the killer or anyone says ,
this isn 't my story .
- [ honks ] - [ Richie ] All right !
Let 's get the fuck out of town , huh ?
Sorry . That 's my boyfriend , Richie .
Nice to meet ... We met .
Sam , please get in the car so we never have to see these people again .
- Sam ... - No . We 're leaving .
That 's the only way I can protect Tara .
Okay , good luck .
You too .
Well , that went fucking horribly .
Don 't worry , I have a plan . She seems really tough .
Honestly , Sid , who gives a shit ?
You said it yourself , he 's gonna go after her .
I put a tracker on her car .
- You did what ? - It seemed like something
Gale Weathers would do .
Take that as a compliment .
I left a message for Mom . I told her where we 're going .
Fuck , where is it ?
[ Sam ] Where 's what ?
My inhaler . I usually keep an extra one .
Should we go back ?
Whoa . Okay .
I vote for not going back to the murder hospital .
- You want to stop at a pharmacy ? - I 'd need a prescription .
But I left an extra one at Amber 's .
- Her house is on the way . - No . No . No , no , no .
I 'd be in and out .
Could you hold out till Modesto ?
- I don 't think so . - Okay , what 's the address ?
123 No Fucking Way Lane .
Richie , she needs it .
And I need to keep all the blood inside my body . So do you .
Richie , please .
It 's okay .
Okay , yeah . Fuck . What 's the goddamn address ?
[ " Pressure " playing on speakers ]
[ partygoers laughing , chattering ]
[ music continues ]
Keep pouring , Wheeler . Thank you .
Hey .
To Wes !
[ all ] To Wes !
Beautiful son of a bitch .
[ woman ] We love you , buddy !
Shots , really ? This is supposed to be a memorial .
Well , this is how I mourn
and distract myself from the looming specter of Death .
Hey , we 're low on beer .
There 's more in the basement . I 'll go get some .
[ sighs ]
[ gasps ]
What the fuck , Mindy ? Jesus !
That was a test . And you failed .
Never go off on your own with a masked killer around .
You 're the one that said we needed more beer .
And you should have asked me to come with you .
[ chuckles ]
You know what else you shouldn 't do
when there 's a masked killer around ?
What ?
Follow someone into a dark , creepy basement alone .
I mean ...
[ chuckles ]
... how do you know I 'm not the killer ?
Because I am .
I 'm not , actually .
But let that be a lesson . Don 't trust anyone .
Then how can I trust you when you say you 're not the killer ?
Exactly .
You 're learning .
Now let 's go back upstairs .
You first .
Very good .
I think ... Think I 'm ready .
I mean , I think we should .
Like now . You want to go upstairs ?
Like ... Like upstairs ?
Uh-huh . Right now .
Um ...
Don 't take this the wrong way , but I think I have to pass on that .
[ chuckles ] What ?
Why ?
[ stammers ]
You know , I 'm not like entirely sure that you 're not the ...
killer .
" Don 't take this the wrong way " ?
No , no , look . I 'm almost 100 % certain that you are not ,
but the safest option is to be down here
with all the people ...
Fuck you .
... and the potential witnesses .
That is a completely valid emotional response to have .
- That too . - Fucking asshole .
Good job .
Fuck you , Mindy .
If I hadn 't have written that book about your mother ,
- none of this would 've happened . - Gale .
- I started all of this . - No , you didn 't .
Billy Loomis started this , and we 're gonna end it .
After tonight , no more books ,
no more movies , no more fucking Ghostface .
- Don 't you know the rules ? - What rules ?
[ laughs ]
[ Movie Randy on TV ] There are specific rules
that one must abide by to successfully survive a horror movie .
For instance ,
number one ...
[ Mindy ] Don 't do it . Don 't go outside after her .
She 's not texting me back .
Because she 's probably dead .
Jesus , Mindy .
That 's my girlfriend , and I love her .
Was your girlfriend .
You 're just gonna sit and watch a movie about our uncle getting stabbed ?
It calms me down , okay ? I 'm also gonna smoke some weed
and possibly hook up with Frances .
Have fun .
Oh , my God , at least take some sort of weapon .
Here you go .
[ music pounding in distance ]
[ cell phone beeps ]
All right .
[ chuckles ] What ?
[ chuckles ]
- [ beeping ] - Ah .
[ beeping continues ]
[ bushes rustle ]
Liv ?
[ beeping continues ]
[ bushes rustling ]
Liv ?
[ beeping continues ]
[ beeping quickens ]
All right . Okay , yeah , no .
Shit !
[ screams ]
[ groaning ]
[ groans ] Fuck !
[ beeping continues ]
[ beeping quickens ]
Please , please , please .
[ groans ]
Whoa ! Stop ! Wait !
[ grunting ]
[ groans ]
Oh , perfect . She 's having a party .
Who has a party in the middle of a killing spree ?
- Look , I 'm aborting the plan . - No , we 're already here .
I 'll go in quickly and get it . I 'll be back in five .
I 'm coming too .
If you think I 'm waiting out here
just to get murdered , you 're out of your mind .
[ cheering ]
Tara !
What are you doing out of the hospital ?
Should you even be up and around ?
- I need my spare inhaler . - Why ? Where are you going ?
It 's fine . Don 't tell me . I get it . Just be safe , okay ?
I think it 's in my room .
All right , everyone !
Thanks for coming , but the party 's over !
- Time to go ! - Why ?
[ partygoer 1 ] But it 's so early !
Let 's go .
Hey , hey , hey ! Hello ! Can we cut the music , please ?
[ music stops ]
Uh , hi ... Gen Z. How are you ? Um ...
Both Sam and Tara here have been attacked by the killer twice .
And now they 're here , which makes this place a huge murder target , so ...
if I were you , I would probably leave .
[ booing , murmuring ]
Okay , I tried to be nice . Get the fuck out !
Please get the fuck out .
- Sincerely , get the fuck out . - Buzzkill !
[ Richie ] Thank you . Thank you all .
I 'm saving your life . I promise .
- Thanks , teens . - [ murmuring continues ]
Thank you so much .
- [ plastic cup clatters ] - Thank you for leaving the cup .
Thank you .
Saving your life .
I 'm saving your life .
Saving your life , thank you .
[ Randy on TV ] And number three :
Never , ever , ever , under any circumstances ,
say , " I 'll be right back . "
' Cause you won 't be back .
[ partygoer 2 ] Hey , somebody 's goofy-ass dad 's kicking us out .
Goddamn it .
Thank you .
Thanks , guys , have a good night .
- [ Frances ] You have my number . - Bye .
- Bye . - [ grunts ]
[ laughs ]
[ Richie ] Hi . Uh ...
Is there any beer left ? There 's none in the kitchen .
Yes , Richie , there 's beer in the basement .
Right behind you . Basement .
Yeah .
Do you want to , uh , come with me ?
[ laughs ] No . But you were right to ask .
Yeah . Um ...
Okay , I 'll be right back ... Aha !
[ both laugh ]
- Yeah . Yeah . - Okay .
Well , he 's dead .
The goddamn fucking Uber canceled on me !
[ sighs ] Great .
Now I can 't have sex ,
and I can 't get a ride home .
Could this night get any shittier ?
Liv , where 's my brother ?
What ? I don 't know , Mindy .
Probably off accusing everyone of being the killer !
He actually went looking for you .
I didn 't see him . Okay ?
Why are you looking at me like that ?
Just revising my suspect list .
Fuck this !
Are you afraid of me , Mindy ?
[ chuckles ]
You think I did something to your brother ? Huh ?
You think I 'm gonna ... cut you up ?
A little bit now ... yeah .
I thought you said I was too boring to be the killer .
Maybe that 's the twist .
What do you think , huh ? You 're the expert .
You know what eventually happens to the expert ?
What ?
[ chuckles ]
Enjoy your stupid movie .
Fucking psycho .
They stopped .
- Gas station ? - No . I ...
- Oh , shit . - What ?
Oh , shit . How far are we ?
[ Sidney ] Too far .
Damn it .
Tara , we 're leaving !
[ cell phone ringing ]
Hello .
You need to get out of that house right now .
How do you know where I am ?
You 're in Stu Macher 's house ,
where your dad and Stu killed everyone .
Someone planned to get you there .
You need to get the fuck out , Sam !
No , Jamie . Watch out .
- [ chuckles ] - Watch out , Jamie .
You know he 's around .
- [ Mindy ] What ? - There he is .
Come on , man , turn around ! Turn around ! Dude !
- [ Randy on TV ] I told you . - [ chuckles ]
I told you , he 's around the corner . Jamie .
- Look behind you . - No , Randy , look behind you .
Come on , man , turn around !
Dude , what are you doing ? You can do it !
These are your rules ! Own that shit .
[ Randy on TV ] Behind you ! Turn around .
Look behind ...
Oh , shit !
- [ Mindy screams ] - [ furniture clattering ]
[ Mindy grunting ]
- Mindy . - That 's a lot of blood , Sam .
No , Mindy , stay with me .
[ screams ] What did you do to her ?
Nothing . No , I didn 't do anything .
- The killer , he ... - [ Tara ] Mindy !
What the fuck ?
Richie , where the fuck were you ?
I went into the basement to get beer .
You went to the basement alone ?
I asked her to come with me ! She said no !
- [ door slams open ] - Fuck !
Stay the fuck back .
Jesus Christ !
I was with Tara ,
but the rest of you were wandering around .
One of you is the fucking killer !
Fuck you , Amber . Fuck you !
Why is there blood on your hands ?
What ?
I found Chad .
- I found Chad and he 's ... - Chad ?
- You 're fucking lying . - No .
- You 're the killer . - No , I 'm not .
Liv , stop .
- [ Liv ] Fuck you ! - Liv , just stop !
Fuck you , Amber . I 'm not the fucking killer !
I know .
[ gasping ]
Welcome to act three .
Run !
[ gunshot ]
[ Sam ] Holy shit !
- [ Richie ] Sam , come on ! - No ...
[ Richie ] Run ! Go , go , go ! Go !
Oh , my God . Holy shit !
- Oh , my God ... Tara ! - Wait , no , Sam .
- She has a gun . - Richie .
There are always two killers .
Sam , please put the knife down .
Look , I think ...
- The other killer might be Tara . - What ?
She 's the one that brought us here ,
and you two have been estranged for years .
I mean ,
how well do you really know her ?
Better than I know you .
Sam , wait , whoa . Sam !
[ screams ]
Sounds about right .
You ready ?
For this ? Never .
Here we go .
[ panting , screaming ]
Help me , help me ! He stabbed me !
- What do you think ? - Trap .
Fuck it .
Ow !
Gale ! Gale !
- [ gasps ] - Wait . Let me see .
Let me see .
- You got to go to the hospital . - No .
You said we were gonna finish this . Go finish it , Sidney .
Gale .
For Dewey .
[ clattering ]
Anyone hiding , killer or not ,
you have five seconds to show yourself !
[ thud ]
- [ thud ] - [ gasps ]
- [ thudding ] - [ whimpers ]
Oh , Tara .
Oh , my God .
[ muffled ] Sam .
Sam , please .
[ cries ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ Ghostface ] Hello , Sidney !
Hello there . Where 'd you go ?
[ Ghostface ] Oh , this isn 't Amber . I 'm the other one .
Oh . There 's two of you . Again .
I 've seen this movie before .
[ Ghostface ] Not this movie , Sidney .
You really need some new material .
[ Ghostface ] I got you here , didn 't I ?
You might actually be the most derivative one of all .
I mean , Christ , the same house ?
[ Ghostface ] Maybe so . But you forgot the first rule
of surviving a Stab movie .
Never answer the ...
- I 'm bored . - Wait !
[ screaming ]
Put your hands up ! Show me your hands !
What are you doing in there ?
- Hiding from murderers . - I told you to come out !
I 'm not gonna come out ! You 're shooting everything !
Holy shit , it 's Ghostface !
[ grunts ]
[ coughs ]
[ Ghostface gasps ]
[ grunts ]
Richie ! Gun . Get the gun .
Yeah , kind of hard since you shot me in the leg .
Fuck . Fuck . [ panting ]
- Yes ! Yes ! - Shoot him !
Thank God you 're okay .
[ groans ]
' Cause I really ,
really wanted to be the one to kill you .
Sit the fuck down , Prescott !
[ grunts , screams ]
[ Sidney groans ]
I can 't believe this worked .
I know . It 's a bummer it 's me .
[ in Ghostface voice ] But it really was the best choice for the movie . [ laughs ]
This isn 't a fucking movie !
No . But it will be .
- That 's the point , right , Amber ? - Right , hon !
Third act bloodbath , check . Killers revealed , check .
Time for the big finale !
[ chuckles ]
- Richie ... - Shh , shh ...
[ Richie ] Okay . Okay .
Let 's get ' em into the kitchen .
- Let 's go , bitch ! - [ grunts ]
[ Richie ] Someone has to save the franchise .
You see , no one has made a great Stab movie since the first one .
Not really .
Hey , baby , you want to go get
- the very ex-Mrs . Riley ? - Yeah , I do .
Hey , hey !
Whoa ... whoa .
Sidney Prescott .
You know ...
I 'm a really big fan .
Go fuck yourself .
You see the last Stab movie ?
Not really a fan of scary movies .
That checks out . Anyway , it sucked balls .
Because nobody takes the true fans seriously .
Not really .
They just laugh at us , and why ?
Because we love something ?
We 're just a fucking joke to them ?
How can fandom be toxic ?
It 's about love !
They don 't fucking understand that these movies are important to people .
- Richie ... - We 're gonna help them !
Hollywood 's totally fucking out of ideas ,
so we decided we 'd give them some new source material to follow .
You know , bring it back to basics .
Because that 's how you make a great Stab movie , Sam .
- " Based on actual events . " - [ Gale groans ]
- Gale . - Shh , shh .
[ Richie ] Back up . Back up .
[ chuckles ]
[ squeaking ]
You did all this just to make me the hero
of your fucked-up movie ?
Sweetie , you 're not the hero .
You 're the villain .
The daughter of Billy Loomis
who sees fucked-up visions of her dead dad ?
Sidney Prescott killed your father .
You ...
did all this just to get her back to Woodsboro .
You know what the biggest problem
with the Stab movies is ?
There 's no Michael Myers or Jason Voorhees .
No bad guy to keep coming back .
But the illegitimate daughter of the original mastermind ?
[ scoffs ] Now that 's a fucking villain .
- How did you know ? - About your father ?
It 's a small town , and your mom 's a drunk !
I met Richie on the Stab subreddit .
I 've been obsessed ever since my parents bought this house .
We realized pretty quickly we had similar ideas .
Wasn 't that hard for me to find you in Modesto .
It wasn 't that hard for me to fuck you , either .
But I guess being a sexually available woman
is supposed to be empowering these days .
Fuck you !
Well , now you 're just quoting the original .
- [ Amber chuckles ] - [ chuckles ]
But it wouldn 't work with just you , Sam .
See , we had to bring the legacy characters back to make it matter .
Can 't have a bona fide Halloween without Jamie Lee !
[ Richie ] Nope !
Dewey had to die to make it real .
To show that this wasn 't just some bullshit ,
cash-in , run-of-the-mill sequel .
Because our movie has fucking stakes !
' Cause anyone can die in a requel .
- [ Sidney grunts ] - No !
[ Richie ] Goddamn it . Whoa , whoa !
No , hey ! Sit the fuck down .
I 'm so sorry , Sid .
We can 't let you live either .
I mean , surviving this many times ...
that would just be ridiculous .
This time the fans are gonna be the ones who win .
[ groans ]
- That about cover it ? - Nailed it , baby .
Get Tara out of the closet .
We got to start staging the bodies !
Stay with me , Sid . Stay with me .
[ Richie ] You really should 've listened to Dewey .
He nailed it in one ! Dude , look at the love interest !
Are you fucking stupid ?
I even had you convinced it could be your sister .
[ door opens , closes in distance ]
[ Amber ] Um , she 's not here .
What the fuck do you mean , " She 's not here " ?
[ Amber ] She 's not here !
I untied her .
Guess you 're not as persuasive as you thought .
[ phone ringing ]
- That 's for you . - [ scoffs ]
Yeah .
Like your gimpy little sister 's gonna make a difference .
She 's our fucking pincushion at this point .
Amber ! Fan out . She couldn 't have gotten far .
I can 't find her ! [ grunts ]
[ Richie ] Amber ?
[ gunshot ]
[ Richie grunts ]
[ screams ]
[ Richie ] Sam ! Where you going ? Your big scene 's coming up !
[ Amber screams ]
Fucking kill you !
[ screams ]
[ Amber ] The fucking hand sanitizer ?
No , no , no , it 's not my fault ! It 's not my fault !
Let me guess , the movies made you do it ?
No , it was the message boards ! I was radicalized .
- By movie fans ? - Yes , they 're so mad !
Please , it 's not my fault . I 'm just a dumb kid .
I wanted to be a part of something .
" A part of something " ? You killed my best friend !
Yeah , and he died like a pussy .
[ grunts ]
[ Gale screams ]
That 's the thing about slashers , Sam .
So many blood trails .
This one yours ?
Only one way to find out !
[ grunts ]
I was the last thing Dewey saw before he died too .
I can 't believe I get to do you both .
No last-minute saves this time . Your story 's over !
Time to pass the torch .
It 's all yours , bitch !
- You want to do the honors ? - This one 's yours .
No , stop , stop , stop ! I 'm sorry about Dewey .
Fuck you .
[ screaming ]
Enjoy that torch .
[ Richie shouts ] Stop ...
fucking up ...
my ending !
Sam ?
Sam !
[ both grunt ]
[ Richie ] Okay .
What are you gonna do now , huh ?
Make a scary phone call to me ?
Pop out of that closet in a Ghostface mask ?
No .
Because you 're the villain !
And the villain dies at the end .
Those are the rules .
I 'm introducing a new rule .
And what would that be ? Huh ?
Well ?
[ laughs ]
Never fuck with the daughter of a serial killer .
[ Richie grunts ]
[ gurgles ] Wait !
What about ... my ending ?
Here it comes .
[ shrieks ] No !
Careful , they always come back .
Okay , then .
[ screaming ]
[ gunshot ]
I still prefer The Babadook . [ inhales ]
Are you okay ?
- Are you good ? - [ Sam ] Mm-hmm .
[ police radio chatter ]
I 'm so sorry . Excuse me .
Excuse me , sir .
- Hey . - Hey .
She 's gonna be okay .
Can you take us to a different hospital this time ?
Of course .
You ready to go ?
I 'll be right back , yeah ?
Your vitals look good .
Just sit tight for a draft , okay ?
Sidney . Gale .
Thank you both .
For everything .
Are you gonna be all right ?
I 'll survive . I always do .
You were right ...
about not running .
Sorry about that .
How are you doing ?
Ask me in a few days .
But at least I know what I 'm gonna write about .
What 's that ?
Not this .
Those fuckers can die in anonymity .
But maybe something about a good man
who used to be the sheriff here once .
I 'd like to read that story .
Can I ask you a weird question ?
Yeah .
Am I gonna be okay ?
Eventually .
- Hey . - Wait . Sam , Sam , Sam !
Thank you .
Well , you 're not going anywhere without me .
Don 't worry .
I 'm gonna hold your hand all the way there .
I can take care of her and her sister .
She 's all ready for transportation .
Twenty-five years ago , almost to the day , in this very house
a tragic story ended .
Tonight , a new chapter came to a close .
Police do not have a lot of information right now ,
as they are still collecting evidence .
As you can see , this is a very active crime scene here .
An unknown number of fatalities , several injuries ,
some people being taken off by ambulance right now as we speak .
This is a developing story ...
[ continues , indistinct ]
[ " Fall Out Of Love " plays ]
[ inaudible ]
[ music continues ]
[ music fades ]
[ " I Don 't Want To Talk " plays ]
[ music stops ]